# **Albert Chang**

2084 Mento Dr, Fremont, CA 94539 - (510) 676-0374 - <u>albertchanged@gmail.com</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/albertchanged</u> - <u>github.com/albertchanged</u>

## **SUMMARY**

Passionate web and front-end software developer with 2 years of experience and a <u>portfolio</u> of fast, elegant, and user-friendly web projects. A deep love for programming, knack for aesthetics, and hunger to learn more through courses and hackathons. Educated in back end integration, page and search engine optimization, and UX design.

#### **EDUCATION**

San Jose State University, Bachelor of Science (BS)

**Graduated May 2017** 

Major - Management Information Systems

Minor – Computer Science

**3x Dean's Scholar** – 3.65+ GPA for 2 contiguous semesters (2016, 2016, 2017)

Major GPA: 3.94

### **SKILLS**

- Programming/Languages Java, HTML5, CSS3, ES5/ES6 JavaScript, JQuery, React JS, Redux, SQL, PHP, Bash
- IDEs/Database Tools Intellij IDEA, Eclipse, Android Studio, Sublime Text, Postman, MySQL, MS Access
- Operating Systems/Platforms Mac OS X, Windows, UNIX, Android

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Software Development Engineer Intern – Flex**

March 2016 - August 2016

- Worked to expedite warehouse activities by 30% through Flex's AR application for the Atheer Glass device
- Developed four vibrant Android screens using Java, XML, and multiple UI Fragments to handle state changes
- Made REST calls to global Flex servers to retrieve all data for use throughout application, using Flex's API

#### IT and Intranet Support Intern - Anita Borg Institute at Hewlett Packard

June 2015 - August 2015

- Assembled detailed staff directory page and organization chart of 50+ members via WordPress, HTML, CSS
- Provided help-desk support for security management, software installation, and important updates
- Successfully troubleshot hardware, network connection, and browser issues on 35 PCs and Macs

#### **PROJECTS**

## Portfolio Website - Self (www.albertchanged.me)

**August 2017 – August 2017** 

- Developed aesthetic, responsive portfolio that details latest work and offers insight into life beyond résumé
- Built modals and contact form with Bootstrap and PHP, controlled CSS animations with SVG and jQuery

#### 'YouTube Topics' React Web App – Self (albertchanged.github.io/YouTube-Topics)

July 2017 - August 2017

- Populates search results directly from YouTube's 'Topic' channels to provide highest quality music to the user
- Designed components / states in ES6, organized CSS with Sass, bundled application with Babel and Webpack

## 'Win Her Love' JavaScript Game – Self (albertchanged.github.io/Win-Her-Love)

June 2017 - June 2017

- For a Udacity Nanodegree course. Involves a player crossing a busy road to earn items from the other side
- Created movement and impact logic with object oriented JavaScript, displayed progress with HTML and CSS

#### 'Form Check' Android App – Hackathon (devpost.com/software/form-check)

February 2017 - February 2017

- Team of four. Application allowed users to log in, leave feedback on weightlifting clips, and upload their own
- Directed UI/UX, integrated login APIs, and utilized Firebase to support user verification, data storage/retrieval